Guide to the Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies student papers, 1990-1997.
Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies student papers, 1990-1997
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies student papers, 1990-1997.
23-13-2542
New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies.
.1 cubic ft.
Papers written by students in HDFS 258 (Women's Studies 238).
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers written by students in HDFS 258 (Women's Studies 238). Topics include the Farmers' Wives Reading Course, given by the College of Home Economics, Martha Van Rensselaer, the "domecon" (Domestic Economics) baby program, and a 1948 film about the college. Miscellaneous topics concern organization including the Cosmopolitan Club, Frigga Fylgae, and S.E.D.O.W.A.H. (Scholarship, Enthusiasm, Dignity of Women in Agriculture and Home Economics), and a paper on Flemmie P. Kittrell. Also papers written concerning the Co-Ed Protest, late 1890s, by Rachel Harris and Cathy Hogan.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers written by students in HDFS 258 (Women's Studies 238). Topics include the Farmers' Wives Reading Course, given by the College of Home Economics, Martha Van Rensselaer, the "domecon" (Domestic Economics) baby program, and a 1948 film about the college. Miscellaneous topics concern organization including the Cosmopolitan Club, Frigga Fylgae, and S.E.D.O.W.A.H. (Scholarship, Enthusiasm, Dignity of Women in Agriculture and Home Economics), and a paper on Flemmie P. Kittrell. Also papers written concerning the Co-Ed Protest, late 1890s, by Rachel Harris and Cathy Hogan.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Harris, Rachel.; Hogan, Cathy L.; Van Rensselaer, Martha, 1864-1932.; Cosmopolitan Club (Cornell University).; New York State College of Home Economics.; New York State College of Home Economics.Frygga Fylgae.; New York State College of Home Economics.S.E.D.O.W.A.H.
Subjects:
Home economics--Study and teaching.; Women college students.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- HDFS final paper on Flemmie Kittrell, Tania Germain, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "'Co-eds Protest': A Window into the Atmosphere at Cornell in the Late 1890s" Rachel Harris, 1997-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "'A College of Home Economics': The Movie and Its Implementation" Melissa Eidelheit, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "'A College of Home Economics': Women in America and More" Rory E. Jurman, 1990-04-28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Research Option #5: "'A College of Home Economics': the Movie", 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Assignment #5: A Report on the Historical Research of and Article Entitled: "Co-eds Protest, Row Between President Schurman and Sage College Women" Cathy Hogan, 1997-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Martha Van Rensselaer Her Professional Image and Association with Eleanor Roosevelt" Ingrid Mahnke, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "The Education of Farm Woman: Liberation or Limitation? An Analysis of the Cornell Farmers' Wives' Reading Course" Leah Richardson (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "The Correspondence of Martha Van Rensselaer and Eleanor Roosevelt 1925-1931: Building a Friendship and a College" Tara Sullivan, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Building the College of Home Economics: Martha Van Rensselaer and Eleanor Roosevelt - Friends and Political Allies" Elena Fernandez, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "The Cornell Reading-Course for the Farm Home" Katherine Alaimo, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Practicing for Motherhood: The Domecon Baby Program at Cornell University's College of Home Economics" Wendy Nejman, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "The Domecon Babies" Shaund Burke, 1990-04-03 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Frigga Flygae" Mimi Ka, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "S.E.D.O.W.A.H.: Scholarship, Enthusiasm, Dignity, of Women in Agriculture and Home Economics" Renee Ferr (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "The Mothercraft Movement at Cornell" Jill Myer (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "A College of Home Economics" Lara Greco, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Homemaking Apartments and Domecon Babies" Lauryn Schmerl, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "The Cosmopolitan Club" James Freedus (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "Domecon Babies" Jodie Thorz, 1990-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Joan Brumberg's correspondence regarding HDFS 258 research papers, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)